AMAN GOEL

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science & Engineering, University of Michigan

Basic Information 5th Year Ph.D. Candidate (adviser: Prof. Karem Sakallah) Formal Methods & Automated Reasoning Group, CSE University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA $amangoel@umich.edu +1 (734) 881-0674 \\ aman-goel.github.io$

という

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research interests include exploring the reliability & security of complex hardware and software systems and developing automated reasoning algorithms for ensuring system correctness. I also have a developing interest in blockchains, smart contracts verification, machine learning, and web systems. My recent work focuses on the automatic verification of distributed systems.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA

Aug 2016 - Present

Ph.D. student, Computer Science & Engineering

Grade Point Average: 3.96/4

July 2011 - May 2016

Silver Medalist

Bachelor of Technology, Electrical Engineering
Master of Technology, Microelectronics & VLSI

- Grade Point Average: 9.23/10

- Minor: Industrial Engineering (GPA: 9.33/10)

RECENT RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

O Developer of AVR

IIT Madras, India

Sep 2016 - Present

AVR is a tool for automatic verification of state-transition systems

- Successfully applied on several hardware systems, such as RISC-V cores
- Uses SMT solvers (Z3, Yices, Boolector) to perform word-level formal verification
- Uses data abstraction for scaling unbounded property verification
- Won 1^{st} place in the prestigious Hardware Model Checking Competition (HWMCC) 2020 with 7×7 , 1×7 , 1×7 medals

O Developer of IC3PO

Nov 2019 - Present

IC3PO is a tool for automatic, push-button verification of distributed systems

- Performs automated correctness checking and bug-hunting for distributed systems
- Uses formal methods and problem structure to simplify and automate verification tasks
- Generates quantified inductive invariants with both universal and existential quantifiers

Contributor to Yices with Bruno Dutertre

Summer 2020 @ Menlo Park, CA

Yices 2 is a state-of-the-art SMT solver from SRI

- Worked with the CSL team and developed techniques for quantified SMT solving
- Developed MBQI and E-matching techniques with a flavor of reinforcement learning

Contributor to JasperGold with Ziyad Hanna

Summer 2019 @ Haifa, Israel

JasperGold is a state-of-the-art formal verification platform from Cadence

- Developed word-level verification engines for JasperGold
- Worked with Cadence SVG (systems verification group) and developed algorithms for automatically solving hard verification tasks

RECENT SERVICE Artifact evaluation committees (AEC)

2019 - Present

OSDI 2021, VMCAI 2021, OOPSLA 2020, CAV 2020

Skills

Good knowledge of Python, C++, C, Verilog, Shell scripting Working knowledge of MATLAB, Java, HTML, LLVM Good understanding of SAT / SMT solvers

Selected
PUBLICATIONS

Towards an Automatic Proof of Lamport's Paxos Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah.



- On Symmetry and Quantification: A New Approach to Verify Distributed Protocols Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In NASA Formal Methods Symposium (NFM), 2021.
 - AVR: Abstractly Verifying Reachability Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems (TACAS), 2020.
 - Model checking of Verilog RTL using IC3 with syntax-guided abstraction Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In NASA Formal Methods Symposium (NFM), 2019.
 - Li: Incremental Inference of Inductive Invariants for Verification of Distributed Protocols Ma, Haojun, Aman Goel, Jean-Baptiste Jeannin, Manos Kapritsos, Baris Kasikci, and Karem A. Sakallah. In the 27th Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), 2019.
 - ☐ Towards Automatic Inference of Inductive Invariants Ma, Haojun, Aman Goel, Jean-Baptiste Jeannin, Manos Kapritsos, Baris Kasikci, and Karem A. Sakallah. In the Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (*HotOS*), 2019.
 - Empirical evaluation of IC3-based model checking techniques on Verilog RTL designs Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In 2019 Design, Automation & Test in Europe (DATE), 2019.
 - iitRACE: A memory efficient engine for fast incremental timing analysis Peddawad, Chaitanya, Aman Goel, B. Dheeraj, and Nitin Chandrachoodan. In 2015 IEEE/ACM International Conference on Computer-Aided Design (*ICCAD*), 2015.

Honors & Awards

- Recipient of Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship 2020-21 for outstanding PhD research
- Best student research award in the hardware discipline in the CSE Graduate Student Honors Competition 2019 for outstanding PhD research
- Recipient of Dwight F. Benton fellowship at University of Michigan for 2016-17
- Recipient of research travel grant and Israel travel award for 2019
- Branch position 2 in Electrical Engineering at IIT Madras (Silver medalist)
- Won international 3rd place in TAU Contest at ICCAD 2015 for Incremental Timing Analysis
- Recipient of best undergraduate research project at Pan IIT Research Expo 2014
- Recipient of *Electronics for You* prize for best academic performance at graduate level
- Won National Award for the Empowerment of Persons with Disabilities 2013
- Invited participant at Summer School on Formal Techniques 2018 hosted by SRI

PROFESSIONAL	
Experience	

SRI International (Intern- 2020) Texas Instruments (Intern- 2014) Cadence Designs Systems (Intern- 2019) Flexitron (Intern- 2013)

Selected Courses

Advanced Compilers Formal Verification Advanced Algorithms AI Foundations Data Structures & Alg. Digital Systems Testing

Teaching EXPERIENCE

University of Michigan:

EECS 281 Data Structures & Algorithms Aug - Dec 2017 & 2018 Jan - Apr 2018 EECS 478 Logic Synthesis & Optimization EECS 579 Digital System Testing Aug - Dec 2019 EECS 492 Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Jan - Apr 2020 IIT Madras:

EE 5311 Digital IC Design Aug - Nov 2015 EE 5332 Mapping Signal Processing Algorithms to DSP Architectures Jan - May 2016

Hobbies Swimming, Water Polo, Skating, Badminton, Soccer

> 2 / 2Aman Goel